- 9819218793
- ★ karthikiyer.r@gmail.com
- Thane, India

SUMMARY

Experienced Developer, Mentor and Manager with over 13.5 years of experience in designing, developing executing technology solutions. Well-developed interpersonal skills to forge strong relationships with stakeholders and peers. Effective communicator with clients and colleagues alike. Exudes high ownership levels and thrives on responsibility and challenging working environments

SKILLS

Java Advanced **Spring Core** Advanced Database/SQL Intermediate Angular2 Intermediate Agile Methodology Intermediate **Design Patterns** Intermediate SCM - GIT/SVN Intermediate Intermediate **Spring Microservices** Kafka/JMS Intermediate System Design Intermediate Kubernetes **Beginner** Leadership Advanced Self-motivation Expert Advanced **Decision Making Problem Solving** Advanced Adaptability Advanced

LANGUAGES

English Fluent
Hindi Fluent
Tamil Fluent
Telugu Intermediate

Karthik Ramakrishnan

Vice President

EXPERIENCE

Vice President

JP Morgan

01/2012 - Present

- Leading a team of 8 people and served as technical lead for decommissioning of existing instruction capture applications
- Designed and Implemented end to end Migration Strategy to strategic firm wide applications.
- Up-scaling the team to support technology challenges and knowledge transfer across multiple applications
- Involved in reviewing and providing guidance in design and solution discussions related to multiple migration project
- Preparing and Presenting bi-weekly Project plans and demos with Senior Leadership
- Handled team Performance appraisal sessions, analyzed training requirements and skill gap analysis for a high performance team

Technology Stack - Spring, Spring Boot, IBM MQ, Oracle DB, Angular2

As part of the team my responsibility was two fold

- 1. Development of transformation engine, messaging platform and processing of trades for fund accounting and settlement system
- 2. Team lead, creating jira's, team meeting, scrum master and management meeting

Senior Software Developer

Syntel

09/2010 - 12/2011

- Individual coordinator developing back end application using java and oracle database
- To Develop front end application using Wicket.
- Technology Stack Front end Wicket, Java, Spring, Oracle Databases

Software Engineer

Infosys

11/2006 - 04/2010

- Individual coordinator developing back end application using java and oracle database
- System support role for developed tools and products
- Developing documents for user acceptance testing

EDUCATION

Information Technology Mumbai University 2006 Bachelor Of Engineering

· ·

Mumbai University

2002 HSC

SSC

10th Standard

- Involved in user acceptance testing and defect fixes
- Technology Stack Java and oracle database